citethemrightonline.com 2017-11-20

# Cite them right online - Privacy and cookie policy

## Privacy Policy

 _Cite them right online_ (“Site”) is operated by Palgrave Macmillan, a division of Macmillan Publishers Limited, a company registered in England under company number 00785998 with a registered office at Brunel Road, Houndmills, Basingstoke, Hampshire, RG21 6XS, United Kingdom (“Palgrave Macmillan”, "we", "us", "our"). Our VAT number is GB199440621. You can contact us using the following email address: [citethemright@palgrave.com](mailto:citethemright@palgrave.com).

##### Coverage of the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) that we gather when you are registering, accessing or using our Site and the products, software and services (“Services”) available on the Site, including without limitation access to the Services by or through the Site, any third party integration of the Services, and any software owned, operated or licensed by us.

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for the Services. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to us or on the Site. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as promptly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at [citethemright@palgrave.com](mailto:citethemright@palgrave.com).

##### Personal Information We Collect

We receive and store any information you provide to us. For example, we collect Personal Information such as your name, email address, job title and institutional or organizational affiliation in order to create an online account. We also receive and store information you provide us that is contained in user submissions, including without limitation, figures, datasets and media you submit to the Site. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to register with us or take advantage of some or all of the Services featured on the Site. In addition, we may provide Personal Information to our partners, content providers or other third parties anonymously so that you cannot be individually identified.

##### Non-Personal Information We Collect

We collect certain aggregated and non-personal information when you visit our Site. Aggregated and non-personal information does not relate to a single, identifiable visitor. It tells us information such as how many users visited our website and which pages were accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our Site to our visitors. We collect this information either through a "cookie".

Like many companies, we use "cookies" on our Site. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. We use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of our Site and its Services. You can find out more about our cookies policy below.

##### Information We Share

We do not sell or otherwise disclose information about our visitors, except as described here. We may share the information you provide with affiliates of Macmillan Publishers Limited (i.e. companies in our group) and our joint marketing partners. We may also share the information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These service providers are not authorised by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you: (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; (ii) to law enforcement agencies following an appropriate request; or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use information you have provided through our Site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

##### How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information you provide on our websites.

##### Access and Correction

We will provide users with access to a copy of their Personal Information which they have provided through our Site, where such users are reasonably entitled to ask for this, (for which we may charge a small fee not exceeding the statutory maximum) and they will have the ability to review and correct it, as applicable. To help protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password and user ID, before granting access to your Personal Information.

##### Your Choices

We may contact you by email to communicate with you about your use of the Service. Also, we may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. This confirmation helps us make emails more interesting and improve our service. If you do not want to receive emails, please indicate your preference by clicking the unsubscribe option at the base of any emails that you receive from us.

If you would like your information removed from our mailing list, you may also email us at [citethemright@palgrave.com](mailto:citethemright@palgrave.com) or call us on 01256 302894. When you do this, please remember to state your full name, and the email address you want to remove.

##### Updates to Our Privacy Policy

This Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will post a prominent notice on this Site to notify you of any significant changes to our Policy and indicate at the top of the Policy when it was most recently updated.

##### How to contact us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by:  
Calling: +44 (0)1256 302894  
Sending an email to: [citethemright@palgrave.com](mailto:citethemright@palgrave.com)  
Writing to: _Cite them right online_ , Marketing Department, Palgrave Macmillan, Houndmills, Basingstoke, RG21 6XS, UK

## Cookies Policy

Our website uses cookies. By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.

##### About cookies

Cookies are files, often including unique identifiers, that are sent by web servers to web browsers, and which may then be sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies can be used by web servers to identity and track users as they navigate different pages on a website, and to identify users returning to a website.

Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies. A persistent cookie consists of a text file sent by a web server to a web browser, which will be stored by the browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date (unless deleted by the user before the expiry date). A session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

##### Cookies on this website

We use both session cookies and persistent cookies on this website.

##### How we use cookies

Cookies do not contain any information that personally identifies you, but personal information that we store about you may be linked, by us, to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. The cookies used on this website include those which are strictly necessary cookies for access and navigation, cookies that track usage (performance cookies), remember your choices (functionality cookies), and cookies that provide you with targeted content or advertising.

We may use the information we obtain from your use of our cookies for the following purposes:

  1. to recognise your computer when you visit our website
  2. to track you as you navigate our website, and to enable the use of any e-commerce facilities
  3. to improve the website’s usability
  4. to analyse the use of our website
  5. in the administration of this website
  6. to personalise our website for you, including targeting advertisements which may be of particular interest to you.

##### Third party cookies

When you use our website, you may also be sent third party cookies.

Our advertisers and service providers may send you cookies. They may use the information they obtain from your use of their cookies:

  1. to track your browser across multiple websites
  2. to build a profile of your web surfing
  3. to target advertisements which may be of particular interest to you.

In addition, we use Google Analytics and Webtrends to analyse the use of this website. Google Analytics and Webtrends generate statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the website. Google will store this information. Google's privacy policy is available at: <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>.

In addition to the information we provide in this Cookie Policy, you can find out more information about your online choices at [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

##### Blocking cookies

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. For example:

  1. in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector;
  2. in Firefox you can block all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Options”, and un-checking “Accept cookies from sites” in the “Privacy” box.
  3. in Google Chrome you can adjust your cookie permissions by clicking “Options”, “Under the hood”, Content Settings in the “Privacy” section. Click on the Cookies tab in the Content Settings.

Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain features on this website (log on, access content, use search functions).

##### Deleting cookies

You can also delete cookies already stored on your computer:

  1. in Internet Explorer, you must manually delete cookie files;
  2. in Firefox, you can delete cookies by, first ensuring that cookies are to be deleted when you “clear private data” (this setting can be changed by clicking “Tools”, “Options” and “Settings” in the “Private Data” box) and then clicking “Clear private data” in the “Tools” menu.
  3. in Google Chrome you can adjust your cookie permissions by clicking “Options”, “Under the hood”, Content Settings in the “Privacy” section. Click on the Cookies tab in the Content Settings.

Obviously, doing this may have a negative impact on the usability of many websites.

##### Contact us

This website is owned and operated by operated by Macmillan Publishers Limited, a company registered in England under company number 00785998 with a registered office at Brunel Road, Houndmills, Basingstoke, Hampshire, RG21 6XS, United Kingdom. Our VAT number is GB199440621.

If you have any questions or comments about this Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by:  
Calling: +44 (0)1256 302894  
Sending an email to: [citethemright@palgrave.com](mailto:citethemright@palgrave.com)  
Writing to: _Cite them right online_ , Marketing Department, Palgrave Macmillan, Houndmills, Basingstoke, RG21 6XS, UK
